

Lachlan Sylvester

Software Engineer

- lachlan.sylvester@hypothetical.com.au
- 0405 225 512
- github.com/lsylvester

EDUCATION

B.Eng. (Computer) / B.Comm. University of Sydney, 2001">2001 - 2005

LANGUAGES

English [Native language]

PROFILE

I am a full stack developer with over 10 years of commercial experience with Ruby on Rails.

I have extensive experience of building and leading teams to deliver software in an Agile manner.

I have a deep understanding of monitoring, profiling, and optimizing Rails applications.

I have contributed to numerous open source projects, including contributions to Ruby on Rails.

EXPERIENCES

Senior Software Engineer Nurun Australia (formally Front Foot) January 2012 - Present

- Worked across a range of applications (predominantly Ruby on Rails) for clients such as Telstra, Betfair, TabCorp, Racing UK and Fitness Australia.
- Diagnosed and resolved performance issues using tools such as NewRelic and ruby-prof.
- Implemented caching strategies, such as HTTP Caching with Varnish and Russian Doll caching with memcached, to improve response times and throughput.
- Worked in an agile manner, using sprints to iterate through user stories.
- Integrated with Merchant gateways such as Braintree and Ezidebit.
- Built and consumed APIs to integrate with external systems and as part of microservice architectures.
- · Wrote automated tests using RSpec and Test::Unit.
- Set up CI using Travis and static code analysis using CodeClimate.
- Performed multiple upgrades on major version of Ruby and Rails
- · Managed projects and clients

Programmer

November 2010 - December 2011

Active Billing

- Adapted existing Ruby on Rails based Billing System to the needs of a new client that performed energy cost management.
- Introduced Continuous Integration with CruiseControl.rb and code reviews using GitHub pull requests to improve the quality of code
- · Mentored other developers
- Upgraded an application from Rails 2.3 to Rails 3.0
- Build Sinatra based microservice to generate excel spreadsheets
- Introduced CoffeeScript in improve maintainability for JavaScript code
- · Worked with Ruby on Rails, jQuery and Microsoft SQL Server

Programmer

March 2010 - November 2010

Jobready Solutions

- Maintained and extended Ruby on Rails based Student Management System
- Migrated source control from CVS to git
- Replaced existing deployment practices with more robust Capistrano deployment
- · Worked with Ruby on Rails, jQuery and MySQL

Programmer

June 2006 - March 2010

With Imagination

- Maintained and extended existing Witango web applications, including Revlon Australia website, and the Optus Wholesale Extranet
- · Introduced Ruby on Rails for new projects
- Introduced SVN, and later Git for source control
- Worked with Witango, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server and Prototype.js

∜ SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, APIs, JSON, Git, NewRelic, ruby-prof, RSpec, Minitest, TDD, Agile, Nginx, Passenger, HTML, SCSS, Javascript, Coffeescript, Redis, REST, jQuery, New Relic, Varnish, HTTP Caching, TravisCI, SQL

Designed with ♥ by Xiaoying Riley for developers